Daniel Zhang



comethale772@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/daniel-zhang-121450206

Summary

Professional Full Stack Developer with 7+ years of comprehensive experience in building modern responsive web applications and user-friendly websites using wide set of technologies. Have strong knowledge in developing single page applications (SPA) And Progressive Web applications(PWAs) with pixel perfect UI/UX design. Using logical and methodical approach to achieving tasks and objectives, I can deliver your project on time meeting all your expectations.

Skills

- ► Languages: JavaScript, Python, PHP, TypeScript
- ► Front-end Development:
- React, Vue, Angular, Gatsby, Next.js, Django, Vuex, Vuetify, Nuxt, Redux, Gulp, Webpack.
- HTML, CSS/CSS3, Material UI, Ant UI, Bootstrap, Ulkit, Bulma, TailwindCSS.
- ► Back-end Development: Node.js, Sails.js, Phantom.js, Django, Flask, Laravel,
- ► Cloud Services:
- AWS: Lambda, S3, EC2, Cognito, API Gateway, SNS, SQS, DynamoDB, VPC, Route 53.
- Others: DigitalOcean, Firebase, Google Map API, Heroku, Netlify
- Data Visualization: D3.js, Chart.js, EChart.js, HighCharts, amChart, Leaflet, Mapbox
- ► Database: MySQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, MongoDB
- ► Version control and Team working tool: Github, GitLab, Bitbucket, Jira, Twillo
- Cross-platform Development (Electron.js, React Native, NativeScript, Ionic Framework)

Experience

7 Sr. Full Stack Software Engineer

Turing.com

Oct 2020 - Present (5 months +)

Working directly as Senior Software Engineers to improve technical skills in addition to learning best industry practices. I had the opportunity to create several fullstack applications. You will find some of my favorite apps I've created below; all use React.js framework for the frontend and Node.js/Express.js for the backend. The databases were created using PostgreSQL and hosted through Heroku while the client-side was hosted through Vercel. I used Postman and DBeaver softwares respectively to better assist in debugging the server while maintaining RESTful API standards. I was able to utilize Chrome Dev Tools in debugging the client as well. My time at Thinkful was also crucial in the mastery of version control through Git. All of my work is hosted on GitHub where you can find all three of my fullstack applications as well as some smaller coding challenges

Sr. Full Stack Developer

Upwork

Feb 2017 - Aug 2020 (3 years 7 months)

 Implemented PostgreSQL database in order to persist data and support extraction and insertion of tuples based on chat history and user help desk inputs, employing one-to-many and many-tomany relations to allow for efficient data scaling while preventing data redundancy in an application • Orchestrated Node.js to utilize the full range of HTTP utility methods and middleware, by adopting its ability of shafting numerous concurrent requests while making real-time application much faster and responsive and to use its event based and non-blocking driven server capability if application gets to confront a large number of real-time users

Designed and created websites and web application for various organizations, including e-News and Nepal government, developing custom themes and

WordPress plugins for sites. Leveraged available web technologies to

develop highly interactive sites and boost user experiences. Used server-side technologies to efficiently process user queries and send results.

Technologies used included Java, Spring MVC, Spring Data, JSP EL & JSTL, Use cases, Class Diagram, Sequence Diagram, WordPress, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, and Codeigniter.

Created architecture for and led development of quarantine reporting system for Directorate of Animal Health in Nepal collecting records across all 75

Nepal districts.

Developed Student Management System named Panda SMS which manages student records, faculty information and assign class room student and faculty.

Developed Wordpress based websites which involves custom themes and plugins.



Sr. Frontend Develoepr

Freelancer.com

May 2015 - Sep 2017 (2 years 5 months)

Managed 2-weeks sprint cycle, mentoring junior developers and moving

development forward. Worked in a team to develop the virtual stock trading platform, stock screener, stock alert, social trading features and automation trading. Monitored and maintained Amazon AWS Instance. Technologies

used included Java, JEE, Bash Script, HTML, CSS, JavaScript/Jquery, Jquery Mobile, MySQL, Spring, Hibernate, Active MQ, Maven, Restful Web Service, Test NG, Selenium, GIT, Bitbucket, Github, JSON, XML, AJAX, Adobe Photoshop, Phone Gap, Agile, Scrum, and TDD.

• Full Stack Engineer

Calibro Corp.

Jul 2012 - Apr 2015 (2 years 10 months)

• Engineered Redux(+Saga) for its singleton design pattern with stack trace to invoke action dispatch and handle asynchronous data, while leveraging multiple HOF transformations avoiding rightward drift, ultimately providing predictable state management and easier debugging without data mutation • Incorporated WebSockets to handle concurrent streaming connections between team members so that the client did not need to poll the server on a regular basis, creating a "real-time" experience for users

Education





National Taiwan University

Bachelor's degree, Computer Science 2008 - 2012

Skills

React.js • Node.js • JavaScript • Vue.js • Laravel • Amazon Web Services (AWS) • Django • GatsbyJS • ASP.NET Core • Flask